

Guidewire Developer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution Architecture, Agile Methodology, Gosu, Core Java, Guidewire Studio, SVN, Rally, Tomcat, MS SQL Server



Current Designation: Guidewire Developer Total Experience: 2 Year(s) 8 Month(s)

Current Company: Accenture Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electrical]

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Delhi / NCR, Mumbai Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Guidewire Developer,Software Developer,Software Development,Application Programming,Application Maintenance,Project Management,Requirement Analysis,Solution Architecture,Agile Methodology,Gosu,Core

Java, Guidewire Studio, SVN, Rally, Tomcat, MS SQL Server

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

## Summary

2.6+ years of experience with Cynosure as a Zensar company working in Guidewire application.

Specialization with Guidewire PolicyCenter Configuration.

Hands on experience with major PolicyCenter upgradation project.

Working with gosu, data model, PCF, business rule, validation.

Actively working on Product Designer and Underwriting Issue with Guidewire version 9.0.5.

Having knowledge on Object-Oriented Programming concepts - JAVA.

Sound knowledge on basic Guidewire Integration.

Mentoring more than 8 people for Guidewire fundamental, as well as Guidewire PolicyCenter configuration in my organization.

Followed Agile methodology while working on client user stories and participated in daily scrum.

Understanding and knowledge of Guidewire coding standard, naming conventions and have experienced in code review as a part of peer review process.

Exploring Bundle, Messaging, Web service and Batch Process to get better exposure.

# **Work Experience**

Accenture as Guidewire Developer

Nov 2020 to Till Date

Zensar Technologies as Guidewire Developer

Apr 2018 to Nov 2020

Zensar is one of the leading IT company in service providers in IT. The head quarter is set up in Pune, India. It has started its IT operation from 1991 even though the roots of this organization can be traced back much earlier in 1922. It is CMM level 5 company.

Project

Account : Jewelers Mutual Insurance
Type : Development (Upgrade)
Role : Guidewire developer

Team Size : 6

Technology, S/W: Guidewire Studio, Gosu, Policy Center 7, 8 and 9.

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=e2cd9232c1b0268258f6f5983992a5860e0f0c024f160f1002174409545...

: July, 2018 to April, 2020 Duration

JM Insurance is the largest primary reinsurer farm of mutual companies in Neenah Wisconsin. JM Insurance worked on various LOB like Businessowners, Personal Jewellers, Personal Article farm and business etc.

In this project we configured the User Interface in Guidewire Policy Center according to client requirements.

We upgraded the Policy Center Version 7 to 9. During the upgrade, we configured UW issue for Businessowners,

Personal jewellers and Personal Article LOB. Also supports defect fixes.

Roles and responsibilities

Analysing requirements for development of pc7 to pc9 upgradation.

Participate in daily Scrum meeting to provide daily project status updates.

Worked on editors in the Guide wire Studio to modify data model and PCF files.

Configured the coverages, condition, exclusion and questions set using the Product Designer.

Worked on validations and UW issues in PC9.

Worked on Administrative tasks such as new role creation, providing access, role management.

Interacting with end users on various forums to clarify the functional requirement etc.

Involved in coding and unit testing within strict project deadlines.

Providing warranty / defect fix support.

### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electrical) from Academy of Technology, Maulana Abul Kalam Azad University of Technology in 2017

## IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
Gosu		
CORE JAVA		
Guidewire Studio, SVN, Rally		
Tomcat		
MS SQL Server 2014, H2		
WINDOWS		

## Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Bengali				
Oriya				

### **Affirmative Action**

### **Work Authorization**

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time